A Guide to the Dandridge Spotswood Papers, 1585-1939
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Papers, 1585-1939
Library of Virginia
24974
.225 cubic feet
Dandridge Spotswood
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Martha D. D. Spotswood, Petersburg, Virginia, 30 June 1958.
Biographical Information
Dandridge Spotswood was born 17 May 1872 in Petersburg, Virginia to William F. Spotswood (1827-1895) and Isabella Matoaca Dunlop Spotswood (1848-1922). He attended Pantops Academy near Charlottesville, Virginia, Hampden-Sidney College from 1893 to 1896, and Cornell University of Michigan. An industrial and mining engineer, Spotswood spent much of his career in New York and travelling about the United States and Europe. In 1924, he returned to Petersburg and devoted himself to history and genealogy. Spotswood died 27 November 1939 in Petersburg, and was buried in Blandford Cemetery.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1585-1939, of Dandridge Spotswood (1872-1939) of Petersburg, Virginia, consisting of abstracts, extracts, and transcripts of agreements, bills of lading, commissions, deeds, genealogical notes, judicial records, letters, military orders, and promissory notes concerning the history of Virginia and of the United States. Subjects include but are not limited to: Virginia history from the 17th to the 20th century; United States history from the 18th and 19th centuries, including the American Revolution, the War of 1812, the Mexican War, and the Civil War; history of California, Mississippi, Missouri, North Carolina, and Tennessee; the United States Navy; agriculture, genealogy, shipping, social life and customs, and tobacco. Prominent correspondents include: Aaron Burr (1756-1836), Jefferson Davis (1808-1889), Andrew Jackson (1767-1845), Stonewall Jackson (1824-1863), Thomas Jefferson (1743-1826), Philip Kearny (1815-1862), Robert E. Lee (1807-1870), Abraham Lincoln (1809-1865), Alexander Spotswood (1676-1740), Alexander Spotswood (1746-1818), Benjamin Stoddert (1751-1813), John Tyler (1790-1862), and George Washington (1732-1799). Families mentioned prominently are the Dunlop family, the Spotswood family, and the Dunlop family. Refer to the on-line finding aid for complete list of items and correspondents. Items 138-146 are original documents.
Arrangement
Chronological
Contents List
- Papers, 1619-1935, .225 cubic feet
  - Papers, 1619-1711 (Folder 1)
    - Letter, 14 January 1619, John Pery, James City, Virginia, to Sir Edwin Sandys., 1; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 2 May 1661, Sir William Berkeley to Major Joseph Croshaw., 2; 2 leaves, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 24 October 1659, Robert Peachey, Milden Hall, [Suffolk County, England], to William [Peachey]., 3; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 1 July 1663, Fortune Mills to Mr. Dennis., 4; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 1 February 1664, Grey Skipwith to Dale [Skipwith]., 5; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, January 1683, W. B., Virginia, to Mr. North., 6; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 5 June 1685, W. B., Virginia, to Daniel Horsmonden., 7; 1 leaf, handwritten.
    - Notice, 2 June 1690, petition granted to Captain William Soane to keep an ordinary at Varina, in Henrico County., 8; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 20 August 1690, WFF to John Cooper., 9; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 31 July 1711, A. Spotswood, Kequotan [Kecoughtan] to the Proprietors of Carolina., 10; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1712-1753 (Folder 2)
    - Letter, 1 May 1712, William Pepperrell, Pascataqua, [Massachusetts], to John Vennard., 11; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 15 April 1715, Leo. Tarent, Essex County, [Virginia], to an unknown recipient., 12; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 21 March 1716/7, William Pepperrell, Kittery, [Massachusetts], to Whittemore [Pepperrell]., 13; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 1 August 1732, Richard Bland, Virginia, to an unknown recipient., 14; 6 p., handwritten
    - Letter, 27 August 1732, A. Spotswood, Germanna, [Virginia], to Charles Carrol, Annapolis, [Maryland]., 15; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 1735, William Byrd to Benjamin Lynch., 16; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 10 January 1738, Edward A. Hawes, London, [England], to John and Charles Carter., 17; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Bill of lading, 30 November 1743, signed by Francis Bramham., 18; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 11 May 1749, William Byrd [III], Westover [Charles City County, Virginia], to an unknown correspondent., 19; 1 leaf, typewritten with two carbon copies.
    - Letter, 9 August 1753, Robert Spotswood, Williamsburg, [Virginia], to Mrs. Butler Thompson, Culpeper, [Virginia]., 20; 1 leaf, typewritten.
  - Papers, 1755-1776 (Folder 3)
    - Letter, 5 September 1755, Joseph Ball, Stratford, England, to George Washington, Falls of the Rappahannock, [Virginia]. Newspaper clipping., 21; 1 leaf, photocopy.
    - Letter, 9 April 1757, John Bland, London, to an unknown correspondent., 22; 1 leaf, typewritten with five copies.
    - Letter, 18 April 1758, Clement Read to Captain Bouldin., 23; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Commission, 7 July 1759, appointment of Thomas Bouldin as sheriff of Lunenburg County, Virginia, signed by Francis Fauquier., 24; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 11 September 1761, Captain John Pryor, camp near Williamsburg, to an unknown recipient., 25; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 12 September 1761, Hugh Miller and Company, Glasgow, [Scotland], to Thomas Bouldin, Lunenburg County, Virginia., 26; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 27 May 1764, John Walker to Colonel Bernard Moore, King William County, [Virginia]. Reverse is Moore to Walker, 28 May 1764., 27; 2 p., handwritten.
    - Affidavit, 1 April 1765, of marriage bond between Elisha Farris adn Mary Vaughan, signed by Sam Cobbs, Charlotte County, [Virginia]., 28; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 12 October 1771, Richard Randolph, Blandford, to Captain Theo[doric]k Munford of the Brig Norborne., 29; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 30 March 1776, Tho[mas] Overton, Gloucester Court House, [Virginia] to Samuel Pettus., 30; 1 leaf, typewritten.
  - Papers, 1777-1785 (Folder 4)
    - Letter, 15 May 1777, Chr. McConnico, Petersburg, [Virginia], to an unknown recipient., 31; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 26 July 1779, Charles Nelson, Fauquier [County, Virginia], to Governor [Thomas] Jefferson and Council., 32; 2 p., handwritten.
    - Letter, 30 August 1779, John Smith, Workington, [England?], to [William Hicks]., 33; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 19 November 1780, Alexander Spotswood, camp on the James River, to Major General [Nathanael] Greene, Richmond, [Virginia]., 34; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 21 March 1781, Arthur Lee, Green Springs [James City County, Virginia], to [Theodorick or Richard Bland]., 35; 2 leaves, typewritten with four copies.
    - Letter, 12 December 1781, unknown correspondent to Colonel William Davies., 36; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 2 July 1782, A. Spotswood to [Theodorick Bland]., 37; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 8 January 1783, J[ohn] Syme, Rocky Mills, [Virginia], to Colonel James Wood, Winchester, Virginia., 38; 1 leaf, handwritten.
    - Certificate, 30 March 1784, for membership of Captain Claude Antoine Villet de Marcellin in the Society of the Cincinnati. Original signed by George Washington., 39; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 22 July 1785, John R. Grymes, Brampton Row, [London, England], to General [Alexander Spotswood]., 40; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1786-1796 (Folder 5)
    - Letter, 17 February 1786, John R. Grymes to General [Alexander] Spotswood, Nottingham, [Spotsylvania County,] Virginia., 41; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 18 September 1787, unknown correspondent, New Kent [County, Virginia], to John Hopkins, New York., 42; 4 p., handwritten.
    - Letter, 3 November 1787, Robert Carter, Nomony [sic] Hall, [Westmoreland County, Virginia], to an unknown recipient. Also contains notes on the Gilmer family of Louisiana., 43; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 5 November 1787, John r. Grymes, to General [Alexander] Spotswood, Nottingham, [Spotsylvania County,] Virginia., 44; 1 leaf, typewritten with two carbon copies.
    - Letter, 20 September 1790, John A. Spotswood, Ship Brandon, to General Alexander Spotswood, Nottingham [Spotsylvania County, Virginia]., 45; 1 leaf, carbon copy.
    - Letter, 1791[?], D. Payne to Judath [sic]., 46; 1 leaf, typewritten with two carbon copies.
    - Letter, 10 February 1791, J. R. Grymes and Company, London, to General A. Spotswood, Nottingham [Spotsylvania County,] Virginia., 47; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, [1791], George Washington to the Mayor, Recorder, Aldermen, and Common-Council of the town of Petersburg, [Virginia]., 48; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 8 April 1795, A. Spotswood to Mr. John A. Spotswood, onboard the barque Caesar., 49; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 19 May 1796, John Dunlop, Alexandria, [Virginia], to Manfield and Magee, Fredericksburg, [Virginia]., 50; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1798-1800 (Folder 6)
    - Letter, 15 May 1798, unknown correspondent in Kentucky to an unknown recipient., 51; 2 p., handwritten.
    - Letter, 28 August 1798, J. A. Spotswood, Baltimore, [Maryland] to [Alexander Spotswood], Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania]., 52; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 27 September 1798, A. Spotswood, Fredericksburg, to General George Washington, Mount Vernon, [Virginia]., 53; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 2 November 1799, A. Spotswood to Captain John A. Spotswood, Baltimore., 54; 1 leaf, typewritten with two carbon copies.
    - Letter, 1 May 1800, [Benjamin Stoddert], Navy Department, to J. A. Spotswood., 55; 1 leaf, typewritten with two carbon copies.
    - Letter, 4 July 1800, William Pannill to Colonel John Spotswood., 56; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 10 October 1798, John A. Spotswood, Alexandria, to General [Alexander] Spotswood., 57; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 9 July 1800, [Benjamin Stoddert], Navy Department, to J. A. Spotswood, Fredericksburg, Virginia., 58; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 11 July 1800, John A. Spotswood to [Benjamin Stoddert]., 59; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 23 July 1800, [Benjamin Stoddert], Navy Department, to J. A. Spotswood, Fredericksburg, Virginia., 60; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1801-1815 (Folder 7)
    - Letter, 5 December 1801, Th[omas] Jefferson, Washington, to Governor [Joseph]Bloomfield [of New Jersey]., 61; 1 leaf, typewritten with two carbon copies.
    - Letter, 10 April 1802, Geo[rge] Frohe, Richmond, Virginia, to Mr. James Rind., 62; 1 leaf, handwritten.
    - Letter,, Sam'l Smith, Balti[more], to an unknown recipient., 63; 1 leaf, typewritten with five copies.
    - Letter, 12 May 1806, [Jane Gilliam Hay], Petersburg, to [Mrs. Thomas Colquhoun]., 64; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 18 July 1806, Wm. Aug. Washington, Rock Hill, [Virginia], to General Alexander Spotswood, Fredericksburg, Virginia., 65; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 11 Marcy 1807, unknown correspondent to unknown recipient., 66; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 29 December 1811, Sam'l Hughes, Richmond, to Captain John Hughes, Hughesville [Loudoun County], Virginia., 67; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 11 February 1813, Wm. W. Hening, Deputy Adjutant General, Richmond, to [Governor] James Barbour, Norfolk, [Virginia]., 68; 1 leaf, one typewritten copy and one handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 17 October 1813, General Orders to Petersburg Volunteers, signed by Robert Butler, Headquarters, Detroit., 69; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 24 February 1815, Wm. Taylor Barry, Washington City, to [Catherine Barry]., 70; 2 leaves, typewritten with two carbon copies.
  - Papers, 1816-1822 (Folder 8)
    - Letter, 24 February 1816, Thos. T. Swann, Cumberland [County, Virginia] to Mrs. Sally Macon, Guinea Creek, Cumberland [County, Virginia]., 71; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 25 July 1815, unknown correspondent to Miss Elizabeth A. Robertson, Goose Island, Dinwiddie County, [Virginia]., 72; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, January and 23 February 1818, [Mrs. Frances Purviance], Baltimore, to her mother., 73; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 22 January 1818, John Fox, Oak Hill, [Virginia], to Polly [Fox]., 74; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 5 March 1818, D. Mackenzie, Petersburg, to John Dunlop, London., 75; 1 leaf, typewritten with two copies.
    - Letter, 9 March 1818, Polly Fox to Captain John Fox, Dumfries, [Virginia]., 76; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 18 February 1821, John Fox, Oak Hill, to Polly [Fox], near Fredericksburg., 77; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 16 March 1821, John Black, Holmesville, Pike County, Missisisippi, to Colonel John Tucker, Harrisville, [Brunswick County], Virginia., 78; 3 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 24 June 1821, Anne Grant to Dr. Joseph Green Cogswell., 79; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 9 January 1822, Polly fox to Captain John Fox, Oak Hill., 80; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1825-1843 (Folder 9)
    - Letter, 1 February 1825, John C. Gooch, Lexington, Kentucky, to his sister., 81; 4 leaves, handwritten.
    - Letter, 22 January [18]26, Thomas Jefferson, Monticello [Albemarle County, Virginia], to Joseph C. Cabell., 82; 1 leaf, handwritten.
    - Letter, 29 November 1826, John S. Russwurm, Fredericksburg, Virginia, to Captain John Hughes., 83; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 2 June 1830, Elizabeth Scott [or Stott], Philadelphia, to Donald Mackenzie, Petersburg, Virginia., 84; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 8 March 1831, Andrew Jackson, Washington, to L. M. Cowper, et. al. [Murfreesboro, North Carolina]., 85; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 23 June 1832, Tho[mas] Wallace, William and Mary College, to Colonel Thomas Wallace, Petersburg., 86; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 29 September 1841, John Tyler, Washington to H. A. Wise., 87; 1 leaf, handwritten.
    - Letter, 13 November [18]42, Dolly Payne Madison to unknown recipient., 88; 1 leaf, handwritten.
    - Letter, 9 March [18]43 William S. Swann, at sea near Charleston, South Carolina, to Thomas T. Swann, Cumberland County, Virginia., 89; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 11 June 1843, Daniel B. Woods, Prince Edward Court House, [Virginia], to Thomas Swann, Lyon's Tavern, P.O., Cumberland County, Virginia., 90; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1844-1850 (Folder 10)
    - Letter, 9 July 1844, T. L. Swann, Washington to an unknown recipient, Langhorne's Tavern, Cumberland County, Virginia., 91; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 9 September 1844, J. G. Tannor, St. Charles County, Missouri, to Miss Julia G. Tannor, Wyoming, Dinwiddie County, Virginia., 92; 3 leaves, typewritten with two page copy.
    - Letter, 30 December 1844, J. Calhoun, Washington, to an unknown recipient., 93; 1 leaf, typewritten with copy.
    - Letter, 21 May 1845, from unknown correspondent, Brandon [Mississippi?] to unknown recipient., 94; 1 leaf, typewritten with copy.
    - Letter, April 1846, Sally W. Swann, Guinea [Cumberland County, Virginia], to Thos. T. Swann, Farmville, Virginia., 95; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 10 August 1846, Wm. H. Bowers, Durham [North Carolina?], to Mr. William T. Spotswood, Petersburg., 96; 1 leaf, typewritten, with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 28 August 1846, Robert Field Stockton, Los Angeles, [California], to Secretary of the Navy [George Bancroft]., 97; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 18 August 1847, John Cocke, Dandridge, Tennessee, to John Dandridge., 98; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 20 March 1850, John A. Foster, Kelseys, California, to R. D. Foster, Danielsville, [Spotsylvania County], Virginia., 99; 3 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 2 April 1850, Thomas H. Robertson, San Francisco, [California], to an unknown recipient., 100; 2 leaves, typewritten.
  - Papers, 1851-1862 (Folder 11)
    - Letter, 28 June 1851, James Puech, San Francisco, to S. L. Martel, San Francisco., 101; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 12 January 1852, J. G. Tannor, Dinwiddie County, Virginia, to William., 102; 2 leaves, typewritten with two page carbon copy.
    - Letter, 1853, M[arion] B. Carter, Georgetown College, District of Columbia, to [Miss Mary A. Monroe, Richmond, Virginia]., 103; 2 leave, typewritten.
    - Letter, 2 July 1856, Walter M. Leman, Sacramento, [California], to an unknown correspondent., 104; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 27 February 1857, G. W. Vance to Eliza., 105; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 8 August 1858, unknown correspondent, Santi Espirita, to John D. Duggan., 106; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 13 July 1860, D. W. Vorhees, Terre Haute, Indiana to E. Holmes Boyd, et. al., 107; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 14 April 1862, Phil [Kearney] to his wife., 108; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 16 April 1862, Phil [Kearney] to his wife., 109; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, [May 1862], T. J. Jackson to [Major John A. Harman]., 110; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
  - Papers, 1862-1869 (Folder 12)
    - Letter, 13 June 1862, Phil [Kearney] to his wife., 111; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 13 July 1862, P. Kearney, Headquarters New Jersey Brigade, to Dr. Oakley, 2nd New Jersey Volunteers., 112; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 2 October 1862, R. E. Lee, Headquarters, Army of Northern Virginia, to Mrs. Philip Kearney, Bellegrove, East Newark, New Jersey., 113; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letters, 9 and 13 June 1863, Abraham Lincoln, Washington to [General Joseph Hooker]., 114; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 5 November 1864, E. G. Lacy, the Refuge, [Cumberland County, Virginia], to Lucy A. Christian, Richmond, Virginia., 115; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 5 November 1864, Rose, Marengo County, Alabaman, to an unknown recipient., 116; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 24 December 1864, Colonel William W. Brown, Camp at Gordonsville, Orange County, Virginia, to Mollie J. Brown., 117; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, 19 January 1865, A. Lincoln, Washington, to Lieutenant General [Ulysses S.] Grant., 118; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 18 July 1866, R. E. Lee, Lexington, Virginia, to Henry H. Tucker, Mercer University, Georgia., 119; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 21 March 1869, Alicia and John Scott, Spotteswood, Lauder, N.B., to an unknown recipient., 120; 1 leaf, typewritten.
  - Papers, 1869-1935, n.d. (Folder 13)
    - Letter, 22 November 1869, Roxie [Dearing], Otterbourne, [near Lynchburg, Virginia] to Jennie [Epes]., 121; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 5 July 1871, Alexander W. Weddell, Harrisonburg, Virginia, to Annie., 122; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 18 June [18]72, H. Grigsby Whitehead, Virginia Military Institute to Wayt., 123; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 13 April 1885, Jefferson Davis, Beauvoir, Mississippi. to Mr. Walter Watson [Hampden-Sydney College]., 124; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 1892, Reverend Churchill J. Gibson to Mrs. W. F. Spotswood, Petersburg., 125; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 21 March 1935, unknown correspondent, Halifax, Virginia, to Floyd E. Chabot., 126; 2 leaves, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., Jefferson Davis to an unknown recipient., 127; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., Martha Washington to Mrs. [Anna Maria] Bassett, Eltham, [New Kent County], Virginia., 128; 1 leaf, typewritten with two copies.
    - Letter, n.d., John Orr to his sister., 129; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., S. C. Bott to Frances., 130; 1 leaf, typewritten.
  - Papers, n.d. (Folder 14)
    - Letter, 20 June --73, J. B. Jones, Herndon, Burke County, Georgia, to Mrs. Elizabeth J. Cooke., 131; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, n.d., J. Boucher to Mrs. Campbell., 132; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 3 Marchn.d., S. Spotswood to Miss Sally Spotswood, Manchester, [Virginia?]., 133; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 18 June n.d., Joseph A. M. B. Cotton to an unknown recipient., 134; 2 p., handwritten.
    - Letter, n.d., unknown correspondent to Colonel George Saltonstall, Boston, [Massachusetts]., 135; 2 p., handwritten.
    - Letter, n.d., Polly Fox to Captain John Fox, Oak Hill., 136; 1 leaf, typewritten with carbon copy.
    - Letter, 24 October, n.d., Major George Lewis, Fredericksburg, to George Washington., 137; 1 leaf, typewritten.
  - Papers, 26 February 1864 (Folder 15)
    - Letter, 26 February 1864, Robert [Dunlop], Petersburg, to Willie., 138; 4 p., original.
  - Papers, 1820-1905 (Folder 16)
    - Deed, 25 December 1839, for 41 acres and 62 poles in the counties of Mecklenburg and Lunenburg Counties, [Virginia] from Cleverious R. Coleman and Susan Coleman, his wife, of Mecklenburg County to Cephas Hudson and Pleasant Vaughan of Mecklenburg County. No recordation date., 139; 2 p., original.
    - Agreement, 9 September 1860, between William Luffrey and Robert Lenon Maitland, trustee of Mrs. Isabella L. Dunlop, wife of James Dunlop of Petersburg. Agreement concerns water flow and rights., 140; 1 leaf, original.
    - Promissory note, 10 January 1820, from John S. Voss of Petersburg to Ira A. Easter., 141; 1 leaf, original.
    - Letter, 30 March 1836, from M. T. Hawkins, Washington D.C., to Thomas White, New York City., 142; 2 p., original.
    - Letter, 6 July 1839, John B. Davis, Genito, [Powhatan County, Virginia], to Dandridge Spotswood, Petersburg., 143; 1 leaf, original.
    - Letter, 15 January 1843, A. G. Vaughan, Lawrence [?] to Mrs. Martha E. Vaughan, Jetersville, [Amelia County, Virginia]., 144; 2 p., original.
    - Letter, 18 August 1847, John Cocke, Dandridge, Tennessee, to John F. Jack[?] of Mississippi., 145; 2 leaves, one original and one typewritten copy.
    - Letter, 3 April 1905, Robert M. Dunlop to William B. McIlwaine of Petersburg., 146; 2 leaves, one original and one typewritten copy.
  - Papers, 1585-1939 (Folder 17)
    - Extract, 1585-1586, from The First English Settlement in America: Ralph Lane's Colony on Roanoke Island from Richard Hakluyt., 147; 4 leaves, typewritten.
    - Court record, 17 September 1627, James Citty, concerning Archers Hope. copied from The Cradle of the Republic, p. 148., 148; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 25 March 1640, Francis Wirt to unknown recipient., 149; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 10 August 1678, Richard Clark[?] of London to Ruth Tiplady of York County, Virginia., 150; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 26 February 1683, unknown correspondent to Father Haasmanden of Virginia. Back of copy contains miscellaneous notes., 151; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 12 February 1686, from unknown correspondent to unknown recipient. Copied from the Virginia Magazine of History and Biography, volume 25, p. 251., 152; 1 leaf, typewritten.
    - Letter, 5 April 1687, William Fitzhugh to Thomas Harris of London., 153; 1 leaf, and 2 p., one typewritten and one handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 9 November 1693, Charles Rodes to Sir John Rodes., 154; 2 p., handwritten copy.
    - Letter, 26 January 1699/1700, [Governor] Francis Nicholson, James City [Jamestown], to vestry of Petsworth Parish, Gloucester County, Virginia., 155; 1 leaf, handwritten copy.